A Guide to the Letters from James Branch Cabell to George Jean Nathan, 1921-1936
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Letters from James Branch Cabell to George Jean Nathan, 1921-1936
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
5947-d
This collection consists of 1 reel: positive; 35 mm.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was deposited on 1959 May 17.
Scope and Content Information
Here Cabell discusses The American Spectator, a publication which he co-edited along with Nathan and others. Cabell gives his opinion and makes recommendations and corrections on articles to be published in the Spectator. Discussing American authors, Cabell gives his views on William Faulkner, Upton Sinclair, and Ambrose Bierce. Cabell also compliments Nathan on his Autobiography of an Attitude and mentions his own Ladies and Gentlemen.
These are on microfilm (M-1530), from originals at Cornell University. They are in the order in which they appear on the microfilm.
Contents List
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to______ Boyd and George Jean Nathan 1932 Aug 15, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Nathan 1932 Aug 30, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Nathan 1932 Sep 21, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Boyd and Nathan 1932 Sep 27, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Nathan 1932 Oct 15, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Nathan 1932 Oct 26, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Boyd 1932 Oct 29, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to [Boyd and Nathan] 1932 Nov 25, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Nathan 1933 Mar 8, TLS. l p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to [Boyd and Nathan] 1933 May 6, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to [Boyd and Nathan] 1933 Sep 26, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to [Boyd and Nathan] 1933 Nov 7, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Nathan 1933 Nov 25, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to [Boyd and Nathan] 1932 Aug 19, TLS. l p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Nathan 1934 Feb 3, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to [Boyd and Nathan] 1934 Feb 7, TLS. l p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Nathan 1934 Mar 6, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Nathan 1934 Mar 10, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to [Boyd and Nathan] 1934 Mar 23, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to [Boyd and Nathan] 1934 Mar 24, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to [Boyd and Nathan] 1934 Mar 27, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to [Boyd and Nathan] 1934 Jul 25, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to [Boyd and Nathan] 1934 Apr 21, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Nathan 1935 Feb 13, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Nathan 1932 Dec 31, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Boyd and Nathan 1933 Jan 3, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to [Boyd and Nathan] 1933 Jan 7, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Boyd and Nathan 1933 Jan 21, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Boyd and Nathan 1933 Feb 16, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Boyd and Nathan 1933 Mar 30, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Boyd and Nathan 1933 Apr 29, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Boyd and Nathan 1933 Jul 12, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Boyd and Nathan 1933 Jul 14, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Boyd and Nathan 1933 Sep 30, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Nathan 1933 Oct 14, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Boyd and Nathan 1933 Oct 18, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to [Boyd and Nathan] 1933 Oct 21, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to [Boyd and Nathan] 1933 Nov 3, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Boyd and Nathan 1933 Dec 2, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Nathan 1934 Jan 16, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to [Boyd and Nathan] 1934 Mar 14, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to [Boyd and Nathan] 1934 May 25, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to [Boyd and Nathan] 1934 Jun 10, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to [Boyd and Nathan] 1934 Jun 23, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to [Boyd and Nathan] 1934 Jul 9, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to [Boyd and Nathan] 1934 Jul 15, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Nathan n.d., TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Nathan 1921 Mar 31, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Nathan 1924 Nov 29, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Nathan 1926 May 8, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Nathan 1927 Aug 19, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to [Boyd and Nathan] 1932 Nov 23, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to [Boyd and Nathan] 1933 Mar 27, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Nathan 1933 Mar 18, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Nathan 1935 Feb 21, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Nathan 1935 Oct 7, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Nathan 1936 Aug 28, TLS. 1 p.